Employment Collection, 1817-1991 (bulk 1920-1976)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Journalists: "Around the World with Nellie Bly" game circa 1890 (Box 47)
  - General: "Women's Work Counts" (poster) 1995 (Map-case Flat file)
  - Government: posters from Geraldine's Ferraro vice-presidential campaign (5) 1984 (Map-case Flat file)
  - Labor Leaders: Lucy Robbins Lang interview with Samuel Gompers and with Jane Addams, Hull House (2 records) undated (Map-case Flat file)
  - "Lucia Gonzalez de Parsons" poster by Carlos A. Cortez commemorating the centennial of the 1886 bombing of a labor demonstration in Haymarket Square, Chicago1986 (Map-case Flat file)
- BOOKS ON SHELF
  - Annual Reports, The Jane D. Kent Day Nursery, Philadelphia 1885-94
  - Career Women of America, 1776-1840 by Elisabeth Anthony Dexter 1950
  - Designing Your Future: A Career Resource Book for Women, Governor's Commission of the Status of Women (Massachusetts) 1982
  - Discrimination Against Women: Hearing held of Section 805 of H.R. 16098 July 1 and 31, 1970 (2 vols.), U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Education and Labor: Special Subcommittee on Education, 91st Congress, 1970
  - The Fun of It by Amelia Earhart 1932
  - Homemaking as a Center for Research: Report of the Teachers College Conferences on Homemaking by Bureau of Publications, Teachers College, Columbia University 1927
  - How Six Girls Made Money, or, Occupations for Women by Marion Edmonds Roe 1887
  - A Legacy to Wage-Earning Women by Lucile Eaves & Associates 1925
  - The Little Scottish Whirlwind by Margeret Gordon Carr 1997
  - Locating, Recruiting, and Employing Women: An Equal Opportunity Approach by Cecilia H. Foxley 1976
  - The Long Day: the True Story of a New York Working Girl as Told by Herself (author unknown) 1905
  - Manpower Research and Development Projects, U.S. Department of Labor, Manpower Administration 1975
  - Needed-Women in Aviation by Dickey Meyer (pseud.) 1942
  - Opportunities in the Public Service, Institute of Women's Professional Relations (Proceeding of the Conference, Washington, D.C.) 1939
  - "The People of the State of New York against Charles Schweiner Press," Brandeis and Golmark, Brief prepared, "Nightwork for Women" (unpublished) 1914
  - The Policewoman: Her Service and Ideals by Mary Hamilton 1924
  - The Product of the Mill by Elizabeth McFadden 1912, 1927
  - Report on Condition of Woman and Child Wage Earners in the United States (19 vols.) U.S. Department of Commerce and Labor 1910
  - Report of Proceedings, Working Women's Clubs, Third National Convention 1897
  - Sex in the Industry: A Plea For the Working Girl by Azel Ames Jr. 1875
  - Social Work: An Outline of its Professional Aspects, American Association of Social Work 1922
  - "Souvenir Album," International Federation of Woman Lawyers, 15th Convention, Tehran 1969
  - Statistical Work: A Study of Opportunities for Women, Bureau of Vocational Information 1921
  - Ten-Hour Maximum Working-Day for Women and Young Persons, U.S. Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics 1913
  - "Textile company (unidentified) payroll for weavers Ashvelot, NH, 1873-77" (unpublished)
  - "Their Sister's Keepers: The Woman's Hours and Wages Movement in the United States 1890-1925," Jacob A. Lieberman (Ph.D. dissertation, Columbia University)1971
  - They're All Yours Now Uncle Sam by Max Barsis 1943
  - Thrown Upon Her Own Resources, or What Girls Can Do by J.C. Croly 1891
  - Trends in Part-time Employment of College Trained Women by Eva Hansl 1949
  - Wanted: A Young Woman To Do Housework by Helene Barker 1915
  - War and Post-War Employment and Its Demand for Educational Adjustments, Institute of Women's Professional Relations (Proceedings of the Conference, Washington, D.C.) 1944
  - War Demands for Trained Personnel, Institute of Women's Professional Relations (Proceedings of the Conference, Washington, D.C.) 1942
  - What Can a Woman Do, or Her Position in the Business and Literary World by M.L. Rayne 1893
  - What Have Women Done?: A Photo Essay on Working Women in the U.S., San Francisco Women's History Group, United Front Press undated
  - "Woman's Right to Labor" or Low Wages and Hard Work by Caroline H. Dall 1860
  - A Woman's Work for Women by Edwin A. Pratt 1898
  - Womanpower, National Manpower Council 1957
  - Women at Work: A Tour Among Careers, Alice W. Robinson, editor 1939
  - Women at Work by Betty Medsger 1975
  - Women in Banking: A History of the National Association of Bank Women by Genieve N. Gildersleeve 1959
  - Women in Engineering... Beyond Recruitment, Proceedings of a Conference, Ithaca, NY 1975
  - The Women in Our Life: Insurance, Karene and Anderson 1967
  - Women in the Professions: A War-time Survey, Franklin and Seague, et al. 1945
  - Women in the Workforce: Confrontation and Change, Katzell and Bynam 1972
  - Women Professional Workers by Elizabeth Kemper Adams 1927
  - Women Workers Through the Depression, Lorine Pruette (editor) 1934
  - "The Women's Bureau 1920-50: Federal Reaction to Female Wage Earning," by Judith Anne Sealander (Ph.D. dissertation, Duke University), 1977
  - Women's Work: Up from .878, Report on the Dictionary of Occupations Titles Research Project, Clarenbach, Witt and Nahermy 1957
  - Work in the Lives of Married Women, National Manpower Council (Proceedings of a Conference, 1957) 1958